import { QAItem } from "../utils/types";

export const defaultN400Data: QAItem[] = [
  { id: 1, question: "What does 'claim to be a US citizen' mean?", answer: "To state you are a US citizen", vietnamese: "Khai là công dân Mỹ" },
  { id: 2, question: "What does 'vote' mean?", answer: "To elect new leaders", vietnamese: "Bầu cử" },
  { id: 3, question: "What does 'owe taxes' mean?", answer: "To owe the government money", vietnamese: "Nợ thuế" },
  { id: 4, question: "What does 'overdue' mean?", answer: "Past a deadline", vietnamese: "Quá hạn" },
  { id: 5, question: "What is the 'Communist Party'?", answer: "Like China, North Korea", vietnamese: "Đảng cộng sản" },
  { id: 6, question: "What is a 'non-resident alien'?", answer: "A person who has not passed the green card test", vietnamese: "Không có thẻ xanh" },
  { id: 7, question: "What is a 'totalitarian party'?", answer: "The government controls everything and people have no power", vietnamese: "Đảng độc tài" },
  { id: 8, question: "What does 'overthrow' mean?", answer: "To remove a government from power", vietnamese: "Lật đổ chính phủ" },
  { id: 9, question: "What does 'assassination' mean?", answer: "An action of killing someone", vietnamese: "Ám sát" },
  { id: 10, question: "What does 'kidnap' mean?", answer: "To take someone away illegally", vietnamese: "Bắt cóc" },
  { id: 11, question: "What does 'hijack' mean?", answer: "To stop and steal a moving airplane", vietnamese: "Cướp phương tiện" },
  { id: 12, question: "What does 'incite' mean?", answer: "To encourage", vietnamese: "Kích động" },
  { id: 13, question: "What does 'genocide' mean?", answer: "To kill a whole race", vietnamese: "Diệt chủng" },
  { id: 14, question: "What does 'torture' mean?", answer: "To hurt someone physically", vietnamese: "Tra tấn" },
  { id: 15, question: "What is 'national origin'?", answer: "Where a person is from", vietnamese: "Nguồn gốc quốc gia" },
  { id: 16, question: "What is a 'police unit'?", answer: "A group that protects a community", vietnamese: "Đơn vị cảnh sát" },
  { id: 17, question: "What is a 'military unit'?", answer: "A group works for the government", vietnamese: "Đơn vị quân đội" },
  { id: 18, question: "What is a 'vigilante unit'?", answer: "A group acts like the police, but are not the police", vietnamese: "Nhóm tự xử" },
  { id: 19, question: "What is a 'paramilitary unit'?", answer: "Like a military group, but it is not official", vietnamese: "Nhóm bán quân sự" },
  { id: 20, question: "What is a 'rebel group'?", answer: "A group that fights a government", vietnamese: "Nhóm nổi dậy" },
  { id: 21, question: "What is a 'self-defense unit'?", answer: "A group protects a place", vietnamese: "Nhóm tự vệ" },
  { id: 22, question: "What is a 'guerrilla group'?", answer: "A group uses weapons to attack the government", vietnamese: "Nhóm du kích" },
  { id: 23, question: "What is 'prison'?", answer: "A place where prisoners are kept", vietnamese: "Nhà tù" },
  { id: 24, question: "What does 'detained' mean?", answer: "Held in custody by police", vietnamese: "Bị tạm giữ" },
  { id: 25, question: "What is 'jail'?", answer: "A place where prisoners are kept", vietnamese: "Nhà tù" },
  { id: 26, question: "What is a 'detention facility'?", answer: "A place where people are forced to stay", vietnamese: "Nơi giam giữ" },
  { id: 27, question: "What is a 'prison camp'?", answer: "A place to keep enemy soldiers", vietnamese: "Trại tù binh" },
  { id: 28, question: "What is a 'labor camp'?", answer: "A place to force people to work", vietnamese: "Trại lao động cưỡng bức" },
  { id: 29, question: "What does 'threaten' mean?", answer: "To warn to hurt someone", vietnamese: "Đe dọa" },
  { id: 30, question: "What is 'weapons training'?", answer: "To learn how to use a gun", vietnamese: "Học dùng vũ khí" },
  { id: 31, question: "What is a 'weapon'?", answer: "Like a knife or gun", vietnamese: "Vũ khí" },
  { id: 32, question: "What is 'paramilitary training'?", answer: "Learning to fight in combat", vietnamese: "Huấn luyện bán quân sự" },
  { id: 33, question: "What is 'military type training'?", answer: "Learning to fight in combat", vietnamese: "Huấn luyện kiểu quân đội" },
  { id: 34, question: "What does 'conscript' mean?", answer: "To require someone to join the army", vietnamese: "Bắt đi lính" },
  { id: 35, question: "What does 'enlist' mean?", answer: "To sign up, in the Armed Forces", vietnamese: "Tự nguyện nhập ngũ" },
  { id: 36, question: "What does 'recruit' mean?", answer: "To ask", vietnamese: "Tuyển mộ" },
  { id: 37, question: "What does 'hostilities' mean?", answer: "Fighting in the war", vietnamese: "Chiến sự" },
  { id: 38, question: "What does 'crime' mean?", answer: "An action that breaks the law", vietnamese: "Tội phạm" },
  { id: 39, question: "What does 'arrested' mean?", answer: "Handcuffed by the police", vietnamese: "Bị bắt" },
  { id: 40, question: "What does 'commit a crime' mean?", answer: "To do something that breaks the law", vietnamese: "Phạm tội" },
  { id: 41, question: "What does 'offense' mean?", answer: "A minor crime", vietnamese: "Lỗi nhẹ" },
  { id: 42, question: "What does 'cited' mean?", answer: "Given a ticket by police", vietnamese: "Bị phạt" },
  { id: 43, question: "What does 'charged' mean?", answer: "Police tell you that you did something illegal", vietnamese: "Bị buộc tội" },
  { id: 44, question: "What does 'confined' mean?", answer: "To be kept in a place", vietnamese: "Bị giam giữ" },
  { id: 45, question: "What is a 'suspended sentence'?", answer: "Delaying of sentence", vietnamese: "Hoãn thi hành án" },
  { id: 46, question: "What does 'parole' mean?", answer: "The early release of a prisoner ", vietnamese: "Thả tù trước hạn" },
  { id: 47, question: "What does 'probation' mean?", answer: "You report to an officer regularly instead of jail time", vietnamese: "Quản chế" },
  { id: 48, question: "What does 'prostitute' mean?", answer: "Someone who has sex for money", vietnamese: "Gái mại dâm" },
  { id: 49, question: "What does 'manufacture' mean?", answer: "To make something", vietnamese: "Sản xuất" },
  { id: 50, question: "What does 'procure' mean?", answer: "To find someone for sex", vietnamese: "Môi giới mại dâm" },
  { id: 51, question: "What does 'produce' mean?", answer: "To make something", vietnamese: "Sản xuất" },
  { id: 52, question: "What does 'dispense' mean?", answer: "To supply something", vietnamese: "Phân phát" },
  { id: 53, question: "What does 'cultivate' mean?", answer: "To grow plants", vietnamese: "Trồng trọt" },
  { id: 54, question: "What does 'distribute' mean?", answer: "To supply something", vietnamese: "Phân phối" },
  { id: 55, question: "What are 'illegal drugs or narcotics'?", answer: "Like heroin or cocain", vietnamese: "Ma túy bất hợp pháp" },
  { id: 56, question: "What does 'smuggle' mean?", answer: "Take things to a country illegally", vietnamese: "Buôn lậu" },
  { id: 57, question: "What is 'drug paraphernalia'?", answer: "Equipment to make illegal drugs", vietnamese: "Dụng cụ ma túy" },
  { id: 58, question: "What are 'controlled substances'?", answer: "Regulated drugs. You can buy it with a prescription but with restrictions", vietnamese: "Thuốc kiểm soát" },
  { id: 59, question: "What is an 'immigration benefit'?", answer: "Things like visa, green card or citizenship.", vietnamese: "Lợi ích nhập cư" },
  { id: 60, question: "What is a 'dependent'?", answer: "Someone who relies on another person", vietnamese: "Người phụ thuộc" },
  { id: 61, question: "What does 'gamble' mean?", answer: "To play a game for money", vietnamese: "Đánh bạc" },
  { id: 62, question: "What is 'misrepresentation'?", answer: "To lie or give wrong information", vietnamese: "Khai gian" },
  { id: 63, question: "What does 'pay alimony' mean?", answer: "Pay money to ex-spouse after a divorce", vietnamese: "Trả cấp dưỡng" },
  { id: 64, question: "What is a 'public benefit'?", answer: "Welfare, like food stamps, housing", vietnamese: "Phúc lợi xã hội" },
  { id: 65, question: "What does 'fraudulent' mean?", answer: "To claim something that is not true", vietnamese: "Gian lận" },
  { id: 66, question: "What does 'lie' mean?", answer: "To say something that is not true", vietnamese: "Nói dối" },
  { id: 67, question: "What does 'misleading' mean?", answer: "Giving the wrong idea", vietnamese: "Gây hiểu nhầm" },
  { id: 68, question: "What is 'admission into the US'?", answer: "A right to enter the United States", vietnamese: "Được vào Mỹ" },
  { id: 69, question: "What are 'deportation proceedings'?", answer: "A Process of removing a person", vietnamese: "Thủ tục trục xuất" },
  { id: 70, question: "What is 'rescission'?", answer: "To take back a decision", vietnamese: "Thu hồi" },
  { id: 71, question: "What is 'Selective Service'?", answer: "Services in the Armed Forces under law", vietnamese: "Nghĩa vụ quân sự" },
  { id: 72, question: "What does 'deport' mean?", answer: "To force a person to leave a country", vietnamese: "Trục xuất" },
  { id: 73, question: "What does 'drafted' mean?", answer: "Being selected as a soldier", vietnamese: "Bị gọi nhập ngũ" },
  { id: 74, question: "What are the 'US Armed Forces'?", answer: "US military navy air force", vietnamese: "Quân đội Mỹ" },
  { id: 75, question: "What does 'avoid being drafted' mean?", answer: "To prevent being selected as a soldier", vietnamese: "Tránh đi lính" },
  { id: 76, question: "What is 'order of nobility'?", answer: "Like King or Queen", vietnamese: "Tước hiệu quý tộc" },
  { id: 77, question: "What is a 'hereditary title'?", answer: "A royal title, like Prince or Princess", vietnamese: "Tước hiệu truyền đời" },
  { id: 78, question: "What is the 'Constitution'?", answer: "It is the supreme law of the land", vietnamese: "Hiến pháp" },
  { id: 79, question: "What is the 'oath of allegiance'?", answer: "A promise to be loyal to the United States", vietnamese: "Lời thề trung thành" },
  { id: 80, question: "What is the 'form of government' of the US?", answer: "Republic", vietnamese: "Chính quyền cộng hòa" },
  { id: 81, question: "What are 'non-combatant services'?", answer: "Services that do not involve combat", vietnamese: "Dịch vụ không chiến đấu" },
  { id: 82, question: "What is a 'civilian'?", answer: "A person who is not in the military", vietnamese: "Dân thường" },
  { id: 83, question: "What is 'work of national importance'?", answer: "Tasks that are important to a nation", vietnamese: "Công việc cho quốc gia" },
  { id: 84, question: "What is 'civilian direction'?", answer: "A direction from a person who is not in the military", vietnamese: "Chỉ đạo của dân thường" },
  { id: 85, question: "What is 'conspired'?", answer: "Planned with others", vietnamese: "Âm mưu" },
  { id: 86, question: "What is 'engaged in'?", answer: "Participated in", vietnamese: "Tham gia" },
  { id: 87, question: "What is 'associated with'?", answer: "connected to", vietnamese: "Có liên quan với" },
  { id: 88, question: "What is 'attempt'?", answer: "to try", vietnamese: "Cố gắng" },
  { id: 89, question: "What is 'joined'?", answer: "To become a member of", vietnamese: "Tham gia" },
  { id: 90, question: "What is 'membership'?", answer: "The state of being a member", vietnamese: "Thành viên" },
  { id: 91, question: "What is 'group'?", answer: "A number of people or things that are located close together", vietnamese: "Nhóm" },
  { id: 92, question: "What is 'political party'?", answer: "A group of people with a common purpose", vietnamese: "Đảng chính trị" },
  { id: 93, question: "What is the 'owe' meaning'?", answer: "To have a debt", vietnamese: "Nợ" },
  { id: 94, question: "What is 'file a tax return'?", answer: "send a tax form to the government", vietnamese: "Thuế" },
  { id: 95, question: "What is 'involved in'?", answer: "took part in", vietnamese: "Tham gia vào" },
  { id: 96, question: "What is 'opposition'?", answer: "going against something", vietnamese: "Phản đối" },
  { id: 97, question: "What is 'establishment'?", answer: "starting or creating a group", vietnamese: "Thành lập" },
  { id: 98, question: "What is 'unconstitution'?", answer: "methods that go against the constitution", vietnamese: "Trái hiến pháp" },
  { id: 99, question: "What is 'unlawful'?", answer: "Against the law", vietnamese: "Trái pháp luật" },
  { id: 100, question: "What is 'assalt'?", answer: "To attack someone", vietnamese: "Tấn công" },
  { id: 101, question: "What is 'sabotage'?", answer: "To destroy something", vietnamese: "Phá hoại" },
  { id: 102, question: "What is 'sentence'?", answer: "a punishment under the law", vietnamese: "bản án" },
  { id: 103, question: "What is 'convited'?", answer: "to be found guilty of a crime under the law", vietnamese: "bị buộc tội" }
];
